Finding Aid for James W. Guthrie papers, 1845-1907
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
James W. Guthrie papers
1845-1907
Guthrie, James W. (James Welch), 1827-1911.
86648 Aa 2
Resident of Wooster, Ohio (later of Bedford, Iowa); 1862 graduate of the University of Michigan Department of Medicine and Surgery; surgeon in the 20th Ohio Volunteer Infantry during the Civil War. Civil War letters, diaries, newspapers, miscellanea and photographs; Civil War letters of his brother John Guthrie, also with the 20th Ohio Volunteer Infantry; and manuscript biography written by Helen Stephenson Guthrie.
0.4 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. Elizabeth Guthrie Foster (donor no. 6305 ) and came to the library in 1979.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
James Welch Guthrie graduated from the University of Michigan Department of Medicine and Surgery in 1862. He then enlisted as assistant surgeon with the 20th Ohio Volunteer Infantry. Following the war, he became a physician in Bedford, Iowa. He died September 27, 1911.
The collection consists of school records, and correspondence and other documents relating to his Civil War service and activities.
Subjects:
Bedford (Iowa); Iowa.; Ohio.; Physicians--Ohio.; United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 20th (1861-1865); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Medicine and Surgery. Class of 1862.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Medical care.; Wooster (Ohio)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Guthrie, James W. (James Welch), 1827-1911.; Medical aspects of war.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States. Army. Ohio Infantry Regiment, 20th (1861-1865)
Contributors:
Guthrie, Helen Stephenson.; Guthrie, John.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
- Personal and Civil War service
  - School records, undated; 1853-1854; 1857 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated, 1845; 1850-1859 (Box 1)
    - 1860-1862 (Box 1)
    - 1863-1869 (Box 1)
    - 1870-1879 (Box 1)
    - 1880-1889 (Box 1)
    - 1890-1909 (Box 1)
  - Civil War records, including enlistment papers and special orders, 1862-1865 (Box 1)
  - Journal undated, 1864, 1875 (unbound) (Box 1)
  - Equipment requests and property indebtedness records, undated; 1862-1867 (Box 1)
  - Pension records, 1865-1907 (Box 1)
  - Battles fought by 20th Ohio Volunteer Infantry (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Newspapers, undated; 1863; 1865 (Box 1)
  - Manuscript of "Doctor Guthrie's War,", undated (Box 1)
  - Notes, by Helen Stephenson Guthrie on James Welch Guthrie, undated (Box 1)
  - Diaries, 1860; 1864 (Box 1)
  - Photos of Guthrie and other soldiers, and photos of medical tools (Box 1)
  - Diplomas, 3 items
    (removed to library's diploma collection)